Hawthorne Studies Records on Microfilm. 5856 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hawthorne Studies Records on Microfilm
1920-1961
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
5856 mf
0.78 cubic feet
14 microfilm reels
Articles, reports, pamphlets, correspondence, microfilm.
From the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Collection. Finding aid for boxes at the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee.
5713680
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 06, 2013
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Western Electic; Western Electric, Hawthorne Works; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Educational Dept; Pioneer Youth of America; Rand School of Social Science
5713680
- Material from Box 1: Folders 1-9; Box 2: Folders 1-7 (Reel 1)
  - Reflections of Elton-, Mayo on the Hawthorne project., 1931; 1 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Box 1: Folder 2: Report of the industrial research division on employee interviewing techniques and results and the supervisors' conference program. 1931. Section I of the Report on employee interviewing techniques...is missing.
  - Progress report No. 1, 1927; 2 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 3: On a test to determine the effects of rest periods and hours of work on the relay assembly test group. Up to and including December 3, 1927. Indexed. Appendix missing.
  - Progress report no. 2, 1928; 3 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 4: On a test to determine the effect of rest periods asd hours of work on the relay assembly test group. February 25, 1928. Indexed.
  - Progress report no. 3, 1928; 4 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 5: On an investigation of rest periods, working conditions, and industrial efficiency. August 15, 1928. Indexed.
  - Progress report no. 4, 1929; 5 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 6: Supplementary progress report on an investigation of rest pauses, working conditions, and industrial efficiency,. May 11, 1929. Indexed.
  - Progress report no. 5, 1931; 6 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 7: (never completed or issued). 1931. A collection of notes, summaries, data, and graphs toward a report on rest periods, working conditions, physical and mental condition of workers; and other variables affecting output and efficiency; also, notes on methods used and kinds of data collected at Hawthorne.
  - G. A. Pennock's recollections of a conference with relay assembly test group in 1927, 1932; 7 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 8: From just before the start of the Hawthorne study, to outline the goals of the project and the workers' role in it. 1932.
  - [Materials on the effects of illumination on industrial efficiency and on the illumiriation study at Hawthorne.], 1920-1929; 8 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 9: 1920s.
  - Schedule of test periods for the first relay assembly test room., 1927-1932; 9 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 1: Piece rates and conversion factors for relays assembled in the relay assembly test room.
  - Daily temperature and humidity record for the relay assembly test room., 1927-1930; 10 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 2
  - Vascular skin reaction readings,as a measurement of fatigue., 1929; 11 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 3: Chapter on fatigue from Edgar James Swift, Psychology and the Day's Work. Report from C. E. Turner to G. A. Pennock on vascular skin reactions and measurements of fatigue.
  - Report from Elton Mayo to T. K. Stevenson on blood pressure readings of relay assembly test room operators., 1928; 12 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 4: Hay, 1928. The original document is filed in Box 8 of the original records.
  - Record and menus of meals eaton by relay assembly test room operators., 1927-1928; 13 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 5
  - Daily record of relay assembly test room operators' living habits, including their hours of rising and retiring and their meal menus., 1927; 14 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 6: Arranged by operator.
  - Daily history record of the relay assembly test room experiment., 192 7-1929; 15 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 7: Vol. 1. 192 7-1929.
- Material from Box 3: Folders 1-12; Box 4: Folders 1-7 (Reel 2)
  - Stock list and bench layout used in the relay assembly test room and motions of operators in assembling relay R-1498., 1931; 1 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 1
  - Comments of relay assembly test room operators, 1927-1930; 2 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 2: On rest periods, hours, holidays, vacations; productivity, earnings, repairs, type; test room environment and supervision; job and company policies; fellow operators; and outside interests. Indexed. Arranged by operator.
  - Comments of relay assembly test room operators, 1928-1930; 3 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 3: On their work and personal lives. Arranged by operator.
  - Summary of weekly activity in relay assembly test room., 1093; 4 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 4: August 8, 1931 - December 26, 1931.
  - Personal histories of relay assembly test room operators., 1927-1930; 5 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 5: Arranged by operator.
  - Study of the relationship between hours of sleep and speed test records of relay assembly operators., 1930; 6 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 6
  - Study of the relationship of personal time out and repair time to productivity in relay assembly test room., 1930; 7 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 7
  - Study of the relationship between quality of output and average hourly output among the relay assembly test group., 1931; 8 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 8
  - Study of the quality of products turned out by relay assembly test group., 1930-1931; 9 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 9
  - Report on special relay assembly test group study on the relationship of personal and social factors to industrial effectiveness., 1931; 10 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 10: Original document filed in Box 6 of the orginal records.
  - Output data for relay assembly test group no. 2., 1928-1929; 11 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 11: Original document filed in Box 6 of the original records.
  - Memorandum on the reasons workers restrict their output and do not work at maximum efficiency, 1931; 12 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 12: Original document filed in Box 7 of the original records
  - An observer's impressions of the relay assembly test room, 1932; 13 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 1
  - A study of employee reactions to a shorter work week, 1930; 14 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 2
  - Temperature and humidity data and studies, 1927-1931; 15 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 3
  - Sample and filled-in questionnaires for the relay assembly test room group, 1929-1931; 16 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 4: Questionnaires deal with the personal lives and habits and attitudes and health and goals of workers and their attitudes toward work, and the test.
  - Record of interviews withi relay assembly test room operator no. 1., 1931-1932; 17 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 5: May, 1931 - May, 1932. Original document filed in Box 10 .of the original records.
  - Record of interviews with relay assembly test room operator no. 2., 1931-1932; 18 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 6: May, 1931 - June, 1932. Original document filed in Box 10 of the original records.
  - Record of interviews with relay assembly test room operator no. 3., 1931-1932; 19 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 7: June, 1931 - June, 1932. Original document filed in Box ,10 of the original records.
- Material from Box 4: Folders 8-9; Box 5: Folders 1-5; Box 6: Folders 1-11; Box 7: Folders 1-7 (Reel 3)
  - Record of interviews with relay assembly test room operator no. 4., 1931-1932; 1 (Reel 3)
    Box 4: Folder 8: June, 1931 - May, 1932.
  - Record of interviews with relay assembly test room operator no. 5., 1931-1932; 2 (Reel 3)
    Box 4: Folder 9: June, 1931 - February, 1932.
  - Interviews with relay assembly test room operators., 1933; 3 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 1
  - [Case study of a relay assembly test room operator], 1928; 4 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 2: Operator was removed from the test for health and attitudinal reasons possibly related to her work in the study
  - Record of observations of relay assembly test room operations by D. D. Davisson., 1932; 5 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 3: Vol. I: January 1932 - March, 1932
  - Record of observations of relay assembly test room operations by D. D. Davisson., 1932; 6 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 4: Vol. II: April, 1932 - June, 1932.
  - Indications from the relay assembly test room as to the desirability of a five-day week with standard hours versus a five and one-half day week with shorter days., 1930; 7 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 5: A study of rest periods
  - Daily variations in output by perios for mica splitting test room operators, 1928; 8 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 1
  - Comparison of attendance irregularities among the mica splitting test operators in the regular department and in the test room, 1927-1930; 9 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 2
  - Comparisons of the production of 35 experienced mica splitting operators with mica splitting test room operators, 1928-1930; 17 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 3
  - Mica splitting test room operators' comments., 1928-1930; 18 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 4: October, 1928 - November, 1930. Includes comments on rest periods, hours, holidays, vacations; production, earnings, repairs, type; supervision and test room environment; attitude and transient reactions toward fellow operators; outside interests. Arranged by operator.
  - A report on the length of time required by inexperienced mica plitting operators to attain efficiency., 1928; 19 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 5
  - Comparison of A.M. and P.M. weekly average hourly output for the individual operators in the mica splitting operators study., 1928; 20 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 6
  - Daily routine of the mica splitting and armature straightening operators., 1930-1931; 21 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 7
  - Case study of a mica splitting test group operator's removal from the test for personal reasons, 1929-1930; 22 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 8: Some of the personal reasons may have been associated with her participation in the experiment.
  - Case study of factors influencing a mica splitting test group operator's performance., 1929-1930; 23 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 9
  - Individual case histories of mica splitting group operators., 1931; 24 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 10: March, 1931. Arranged by operator.
  - Interviews with mica splitting test room operators., 1930; 25 (Reel 3)
    Box 6: Folder 11: Arranged by operator.
  - Procedures and studies for establishing bank wiring test room with male workers., 1931; 26 (Reel 3)
    Box 7: Folder 1
  - Procedures and studies for establishing bank wiring test room with male workers., 1931; 27 (Reel 3)
    Box 7: Folder 2
  - Reports on bank wiring test room group., 1931-1932; 28 (Reel 3)
    Box 7: Folder 3: for the period November 9, 1931 to March 18, 1932.
  - Record of observations of bank wiring test room by A.C. Moore., 1931-1932; 29 (Reel 3)
    Box 7: Folder 4: Vol. I: November, 1931 - January, 1932
  - Record of observations of bank wiring test room by A.C. Moore., 1932-1932; 30 (Reel 3)
    Box 7: Folder 5: Vol. II: January, 1932 - February, 1932
  - Record of observations of bank wiring test room by A.C. Moore., 1932-1932; 31 (Reel 3)
    Box 7: Folder 6: Vol. III: March, 1932 - May, 1932.
  - Record of interviews with bank wiring test room operators: Wireman no. 8, Wireman no. 9 and solderman no. 1., 1931-1932; 32 (Reel 3)
    Box 7: Folder 7: Vol. IV. June 1931 - May, 1932. Arranged by operator. Original document filed in Box 10 of original records.
- Material from Box 8: Folders 1-5; Box 9: Folders 1-7; Box 10 filmed as parts of Boxes 4 and 7; Box 11: Folders 1-4 (Reel 4)
  - An interpretation of interviews with manufacturing department employees laid off early in 1930., 1 (Reel 4)
    Box 8: Folder 1
  - Special interviews with laid-off employees., 1930; 2 (Reel 4)
    Box 8: Folder 2: April, May, 1930.
  - Results from the study and investigation of employee comments, 1930; 3 (Reel 4)
    Box 8: Folder 3: On plant conditions and on company actions to improve them; and studies toward the improvement of employee relations.
  - Report on the interviewing program at Hawthorne, 1930; 4 (Reel 4)
    Box 8: Folder 4: For the year ending December 31, 1930, with general comments on the development and objectives of the program and on interviewing.
  - Speeches and articles on various aspects of industrial relations and the Hawthorne experiment, 1928-1930; 5 (Reel 4)
    Box 8: Folder 5: Speeches by G.A. Pennock, M. L. Putnam, C. A. Melsheimer, C. L. Rice, and J. A. Davidson.
  - Interviews with group chiefs by the inspection branch., 1929; 6 (Reel 4)
    Box 9: Folder 1: Interviews L5Q0 and W500 series.
  - Interviews with sub-section chiefs by the inspection branch., 1929; 7 (Reel 4)
    Box 9: Folder 2: Interviews L700 and W700 series.
  - Interviews with section chiefs by the inspection branch., 1929; 8 (Reel 4)
    Box 9: Folder 3: Interviews L800 and W800 series.
  - Comments and reactions of supervisors and employees to the interviewing program., 1929; 9 (Reel 4)
    Box 9: Folder 4
  - Resume of methods and practices used in the employees interviewing program., 1929; 10 (Reel 4)
    Box 9: Folder 5
  - Excerpts from the minutes of the special training course for interviewers., 1929; 11 (Reel 4)
    Box 9: Folder 6: Original document filed in Box 2 of the original records.
  - A mathematical index for interviewers., 1931; 12 (Reel 4)
    Box 9: Folder 7: Original document filed in Box 12 of original records.
  - Projects of the industrial research division, all dealing with aspects of interviewing and the interviewing program at Hawthorne., 1929; 13 (Reel 4)
    Box 11: Folder 1: Indexed
  - Plan for the -industrial research division program during 1929., 1928; 14 (Reel 4)
    Box 11: Folder 2
  - Papers about the Harvard-Hawthorne research in employee relations, 1940; 15 (Reel 4)
    Box 11: Folder 3: delivered at the System Personnel Conference in Southern Pines, N. C., October 29, 1940 - November 2, 1940. 1940. Two papers by M. L. Putnam on the concept of employee relations and on employee grievances and one by F. J. Roethisbergen on morale in a business organization.
  - Seven papers on aspects of the Hawthorne study., 1930; 16 (Reel 4)
    Box 11: Folder 4: Includes papers on interviewing and the Hawthorne interviewing program, plans for 1931, and egocentricity.
- Material from Box 11: Folders 5-6; Box 12: Folders 1-4; Box 13: Folders 1-7 (Reel 5)
  - The human factor in industry by R. D. Gross., 1 (Reel 5)
    Box 11: Folder 5: On the various experiments at Hawthorne.
  - Impact of the Hawthorne studies and personnel counseling., 1955; 2 (Reel 5)
    Box 11: Folder 6: Indexed
  - A study of employees' attitudes toward the bogey system by Imogene Rousseau. 1931., 4 (Reel 5)
    Box 12: Folder 1
  - A study of employee reactions to a shortened work week. 1931. Indexed., 5 (Reel 5)
    Box 12: Folder 2: Indexed
  - Correspondence and materials about Management and the Worker by F. J. Roethisberger and W. J. Dixon.., 1939-1950; 6 (Reel 5)
    Box 12: Folder 3
  - Miscellaneous papers and speeches on various aspects and results of the Hawthorne project., 1928-1940; 7 (Reel 5)
    Box 12: Folder 4: Indexed
  - Training program for supervisors. 1928., 8 (Reel 5)
    Box 13: Folder 1
  - Report on the progress of the employee interviewing program and the plans and budget of the industrial research division for 1930., 9 (Reel 5)
    Box 13: Folder 2: February, 1930. Indexed. Two parts missing.
  - Interviews with employees in the rotational trainnig program in the industrial research division., 1930; 10 (Reel 5)
    Box 13: Folder 3
  - Development work with supervisors at Hawthorne, with a proposed plan for 1931-1932. Case study of a former supervisor., 1930- 1931; 11 (Reel 5)
    Box 13: Folder 4
  - Report of Lovekin and Roethlisberger on the interviewing of supervisors in the operating branch., 1931; 12 (Reel 5)
    Box 13: Folder 5: Indexed.
  - Material concerning the research group on supervisory training methods., 1931-1932; 13 (Reel 5)
    Box 13: Folder 6: Indexed.
  - Splicing operation irregularities., 1930; 14 (Reel 5)
    Box 13: Folder 7
- Material from Box 14: Folders 1-9 (Reel 6)
  - Interviews with operating branch employees about working conditions and other factors which affect their work., 1929; 1 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 1
  - Substance analysis of comments taken from interviews with operating branch employees., 1929; 2 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 2: General analysis of the first six months of the employee interviewing program and recommendations for future interviews and analysis.
  - Substance analysis of comments taken from interviews with operating branch employees., 1929; 3 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 3: Indexed. Original document filed in Box 13 of original record.
  - Numerical analysis of favorable and unfavorable comments from 10,300 operating branch employee interviews., 1929; 4 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 4: Original document filed in Box 9 of the original records.
  - Substance analysis of comments on supervision of work taken from interviews with operating branch employee., 1929; 5 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 5: Original document filed in Box 9 of the original records.
  - Substance analysis of comments taken from operating branch employee interviews taken during 1929., 1930; 6 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 6: Vol. 1. Original document filed in Box 8 of the original records.
  - Substance analysis of comments taken from operating branch employee interviews taken during 1929., 1930; 7 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 7: Vol. 2. Original document filed in Box 8 of the original records.
  - Summaries of comments and substance analysis of comments taken from employee interviews in 1930., 8 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 8: Discussion of the continuing modification of the analysis of comments taken from employee interviews.
  - Minutes of meetings of supervisors from various divisions of the Hawthorne plant, 1930-1931; 9 (Reel 6)
    Box 14: Folder 9: About the analysis of comments taken from employees and suggested actions on complaints turned up in employee interview.
- Material from Box 15: Folders1-14; Box 16: Folders 1-12; Box 17: Folders 1-10 (Reel 7)
  - Index to department 4731 files., 1 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 1: No date
  - Counseling in a group situation by Phyllis Dodds., 1940; 2 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 2
  - The experiment in personnel counseling by W. J. Dickson., 1936; 3 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 3
  - Repeat Of Counseling Activity, 1936-1937; 4 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 4: January, 1936 to March/ 1937. Parts of this document duplicate materials in Folder 3.
  - Counseling theory and practice., 1949; 5 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 5: Indexed.
  - [Notation of the points of view and social interrelationships of departments at Hawthorne directly concerned, with wage problems by E. C. Tessman]., 1936; 6 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 6
  - [Report on the organization and operation of the wage incentives, time standards, and labor grades departments, by E. C. Tessman.], 1936; 7 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 7
  - [Report on employee reactions to layoffs]., 1938; 8 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 8
  - [Work incentives in the station apparatus shops by D. D. Davisson and others]., 1938; 9 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 9
  - [Study of the mobility of supervisors, 1932-1938]., 8 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 10
  - [Report on the situation of inspectors after the hourly wages of some were reduced]., 1939; 9 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 11
  - [Correspondence and report on a conference to resolve a labor-management conflict over piece work rates].., 1940; 10 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 12
  - [Notes on a conceptual scheme derived from experimental data for understanding the relationships between society and individual human behavior]., 1940; 11 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 13
  - [Report recommending the trial installation of a product shop to test the product type of organization]., 1940; 12 (Reel 7)
    Box 15: Folder 14
  - Outline of procedure for setting up an experiment in personnel work., 1936; 13 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 1: Duplicate copies with pencil notes.
  - Outline of procedure for setting up an experiment in personnel work., 1936; 14 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 2: Work and objectives of a personnel manager. Conclusions of a study on rest periods. Suggestions for dealing,with the individual and group problems incident to the change to a product type of organization. Correspondence and reports on the experiment in personnel counseling. Report on employee relations in the automobile industry. Correspondence and report on attitudes of short and long service employees based upon data obtained in personnel counseling. Discussion of rest periods for shop' departments. Miscellaneous correspondence on personnel problems.
  - (Case study showing the impact of impulsive supervisory work on employee relations.), 1939; 15 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 3: Includes final study and a draft
  - {Memorandums on the selection and training of personnel counselors)., 1941-1948; 16 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 4
  - An analysis of a personnel counselor's work. -, 1943; 17 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 5: March 31, 1943. Indexed.
  - [Case study of the impact of personnel counseling on a group of female workers]., 1945; 18 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 6
  - Attributes to consider in selecting and rating personnel counselors., 1948; 19 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 7
  - Report on personnel counseling activity at Hawthorne., 1949; 20 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 8: Sections of the repovt missing and pages missing from some sections.
  - Materials relating to a conference on personnel counseling, 1960-1961; 21 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 9: January 24- 25, 1961.
  - Outline and discussion of the effectiveness of personnel counselors, 22 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 10: No date
  - Orientation program for Hawthorne plant personnel counselors, 23 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 11: No date
  - Study illustrating aspects of the personnel counselor's work., 24 (Reel 7)
    Box 16: Folder 12: No date. Sections of the study missing.
  - A line supervisor's observations on the effect of the counseling program in a conveyor assembly group., 1944; 25 (Reel 7)
    Box 17: Folder 1: Also includes a counselor's observations on the effect of the counseling activity -in a conveyor assembly group.
  - Correspondence of Western Electric Company executives about various aspects of the Hawthorne experiment., 1928-1932; 26 (Reel 7)
    Box 17: Folder 2: March 1928 - March 1932.
  - Correspondence to M. L. Putman and G. A. Pennock from Erwin Schell, C.E. Turner, and R.H. Frazier., 1929-1931; 27 (Reel 7)
    Box 17: Folder 3: February, 1929 - March, 1931.
  - Correspondence to G. A. Pennock, M. L. Putnam, H. A. Wright; and W. J. Dickson from Elton Mayo, F. J. Roethslisberger, Lloyd Warner, and Richard S. Meriam., 1928-1934; 28 (Reel 7)
    Box 17: Folder 4: September, 1928 - February, 1934.
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and materials dealing with various aspects of the Hawthorne experiment., 1928-1931; 29 (Reel 7)
    Box 17: Folder 5: October, 1928 - March, 1931.
  - An account of the work of the industrial research division., 1931; 30 (Reel 7)
    Box 17: Folder 6: Indexed.
  - Some thoughts in connection with work in the industrial research division by G. A. Pennock., 1931; 31 (Reel 7)
    Box 17: Folder 7